<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>mushetty.me</title>
    <link>https://mushetty.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on mushetty.me</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://mushetty.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mechanics: Fundamentals and Applications</title>
      <link>https://mushetty.me/notes/mechanics/mech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 22:19:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mushetty.me/notes/mechanics/mech/</guid>
      <description>Compilation of notes for Mechanics class for Spring 2023.
 Administrative Stuff Lecture 1 Lecture 2 Lecture 3: Lecture 4  Quality Factor Example 1 Example 2    Administrative Stuff  Book: No purchase necessary. Problems handed out. Will be randomly called to solve HW problems HW not counted towards final grade Two closed book quizzes (25% each)  One around March 27 One around April 17   One final exam (50%)  Lecture 1   HW Problems due before class on Jan 23</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundamentals of Computer Systems</title>
      <link>https://mushetty.me/notes/fundies/fundies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 22:19:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mushetty.me/notes/fundies/fundies/</guid>
      <description>Compilation of notes for Fundamentals of Computer Systems class for Spring 2023.
 Administrative Stuff  Exams Grades   Lecture 0 Lecture 1  CPU Models Addition in different bases Definitions Modular Arithmetic Integer format with word size restriction  Unsigned binary numbers:  Binary Addition Algorithm (BAA)   Negative numbers  Signed Magnitude Representation 1&amp;rsquo;s Complement Problems with Signed Magnitude and 1&amp;rsquo;s Complement 2&amp;rsquo;s complement Intuition behind 2&amp;rsquo;s complement       Lecture 2  Why 2&amp;rsquo;s complement?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum I</title>
      <link>https://mushetty.me/notes/quantumi/quantumi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 22:19:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mushetty.me/notes/quantumi/quantumi/</guid>
      <description>Compilation of notes for Quantum I class for Spring 2023.
 Administrative Stuff Lecture 1 Lecture 2  The Current Density Operator (probability current) Erenhfest&amp;rsquo;s Principle Uncertainty Princple Time Independent SE   Lecture 3  Interference of Stationary States Solving TISE  $V(x)=V_{0}$ Infinite Square Well     Lecture 4  Properties of Eigenfunctions Finite Square Well   Lecture 5  Dirac Delta Function Free Particle    Administrative Stuff  10-minute quizzes (5 questions, multiple choice) 10%:  around February 8 around Around March 1 around April 26   Midterm 25%  around March 22   Final 45% HW 20%  Lecture 1  First HW due 6 pm Jan 25th The Wavefunction  Written in 1 spatial dimension as $\Psi (x,t)$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Notes</title>
      <link>https://mushetty.me/notes/machinelearning/machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 22:19:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mushetty.me/notes/machinelearning/machine/</guid>
      <description>Compilation of notes for Machine Learning class for Spring 2023.
 Administrative Stuff Topic 1  Workflow of Classification Problems (Supervised Learning) Statistical Approach  Classifier   Maximum Likelihood Estimation  Example   Convergence Naive Bayes Classifier How do you quantify the quality of a classifier?   Topic 2  Nearest K-Neighbor  Importance of Closeness for k-Nearest Neighbors  Distances Similarities       Topic 3 Topic 4 Topic 5 Topic 6 Topic 7 Topic 8 Topic 9  Administrative Stuff  All homework is submitted via Gradescope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geophysical Fluid Dynamics (GFD)</title>
      <link>https://mushetty.me/notes/geophysics/geophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 22:19:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mushetty.me/notes/geophysics/geophysics/</guid>
      <description>Compilation of notes for Geophysical Fluid Dynamics class for Spring 2023.
 Administrative Stuff Chapter 1  Material Derivative (Lagrangian Derivative) Conservation of Mass Momentum Equation Equation of State Sound Waves   Chapter 2  Why a rotating frame? Derivation of Velocity and Acceleration in Rotating Frames Fluid Equations in Rotating Frame  Encoding The Spherical Earth in Equations Primitive Equations (Dynamical Core, because you can&amp;rsquo;t get rid of the air)  What is $\vec{f}$ physically        Administrative Stuff  Office Hours: Engineering Terrace 287 on Thursdays during class time (4:00-5:00 PM) TA: Eojin Lee el3080[at]columbia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Particle Astrophysics &amp; Cosmology</title>
      <link>https://mushetty.me/notes/astroandcosmo/astrocosmo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 22:16:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mushetty.me/notes/astroandcosmo/astrocosmo/</guid>
      <description>Compilation of notes for Astrophysics and Cosmology class for Spring 2023.
 Administrative Stuff Special Relativity  Spacetime Diagrams  Worldline Inertial Frames Postulates of SR Deriving Time Dilation from diagrams Deriving Doppler Shift from Diagram   Metrics  Metric tensor (SR) Covariant versus contravariant vectors Metric in Spherical Coordinates 4-Momentum  Example       Classical Cosmology  The Cosmological Principle Comoving Coordinates Hubble&amp;rsquo;s Law  Wavelength relation to scale factor   Luminosity Distance (L)   Non-Euclidean Geometry  Metric of a 2-Sphere Metric of the 3-sphere Metric of the Pseudosphere (hyperbolic geometry) Most general homogeneous isotropic metric What is $a(t)?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ML Refresher Notes</title>
      <link>https://mushetty.me/notes/mlnotes/ml_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 17:29:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mushetty.me/notes/mlnotes/ml_notes/</guid>
      <description>Here is a compendium of my notes that I took to review for Machine Learning. This was meant to be a quick refresher on concepts and to put everything in one place. For a less cursory version, see the background section under Resources at the course website.
 Probability and Statistics  Basic Concepts  Axioms of Probability Definitions Baye&amp;rsquo;s Rule Expectation   Common Probability Distributions  Bernoulli Distribution Binomial Distribution Poisson Distribution Categorical Distribution Multinomial Distribution Guassian(Normal) Distribution Multivariate Gaussian Distribution Laplace distribution Dirac Delta Distribution Mixtures of Distributions   Common Functions  Logistic sigmoid $\sigma(x)$ Softplus Function $\Zeta(x)$   Information Theory  Self-Information Shannon Entropy Kullback-Leibler (KL) divergence Cross-entropy Exponential Distribution   Chi-squared Distribution  Basics Goodness of Fit (GOF) Independence   T-test  One Sample Two Sample  Paired Unpaired       Linear Algebra  Types of Objects in Linear Algebra Matrix Operations Central Problem of Linear Algebra  Gaussian Elimination Reduced Row Echelon Form (RREF)  Reading of Solutions of Ax=b from RREF     LU Decomposition  LDU Decomposition   Identity and Inverses Vector Spaces  Subspaces  Orthogonal Complements     Linear Transformations  Diagonalization  Change of Basis     Linear Dependence and Span Basis and Dimension Norms Orthogonal Bases Gram-Schmidt and Orthogonal Complements Eigendecomposition Singular Value Decomposition (SVD) Moore-Penrose Pseudoinverse QR Decomposition  Gram-Schmidt   Trace Determinant Kernel, Range, Nullity,Rank  Mapping definitions Kernel Rank and Nullity   Least Squares   Calculus  Probability and Statistics Basic Concepts Axioms of Probability  Probability Measure $P: \mathbb{F} \rightarrow \mathbb{{R}}$ such that  $P(A) \geq 0$ for all $A \in \mathbb{F}$ $P(\Omega) = 1$ If $A_{1},A_{2}&amp;hellip;$ are disjoint events, then  $P(\cup A_{i}) = \Sigma_{i} P(A_{i})$      Definitions  Sample space $\Omega$: The set of all possible outcomes Event space $\mathbb{F}:A$ is a subset of $\Omega$ a random variable quantity that has an uncertain value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2D Ising Model</title>
      <link>https://mushetty.me/simulations/ising/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 17:09:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mushetty.me/simulations/ising/</guid>
      <description>The Ising Model is a simple thermodynamic model of magnetic material that can visually demonstrate phase transitions. Attached is a client-side simulation of the Ising model that takes heavy inspiration from Daniel Schroeder. I modified his code to be asyncronous, allowed an arbitrary square lattice size, introduced more parameters that could be fiddled with, and added plots to visualize parameters of interest. I plan on adding more detail on the theory behind this model soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Try (and Fail) to Set up a Webserver</title>
      <link>https://mushetty.me/posts/webserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2022 17:09:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mushetty.me/posts/webserver/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to create my own website, so during winter break, I decided to do just that. I could have gone about it the smart way by hosting on a cloud provider like AWS or the like.
I decide to do it the hard way and run my own webserver. I technically succeed. Here is what I did.
In this post, I will be going over what hardware you need, how to secure a Ubuntu server, and how to connect your server to a noIP domain.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
