<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>mushetty.me</title>
    <link>https://mushetty.me/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content on mushetty.me</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://mushetty.me/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mechanics: Fundamentals and Applications</title>
      <link>https://mushetty.me/notes/mechanics/mech/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 22:19:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mushetty.me/notes/mechanics/mech/</guid>
      <description>Compilation of notes for Mechanics class for Spring 2023.
 Administrative Stuff Lecture 1 Lecture 2  Administrative Stuff  Book: No purchase necessary. Problems handed out. Will be randomly called to solve HW problems HW not counted towards final grade Two closed book quizzes (25% each)  One around March 27 One around April 17   One final exam (50%)  Lecture 1   HW Problems due before class on Jan 23</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fundamentals of Computer Systems</title>
      <link>https://mushetty.me/notes/fundies/fundies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 22:19:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mushetty.me/notes/fundies/fundies/</guid>
      <description>Compilation of notes for Fundamentals of Computer Systems class for Spring 2023.
 Administrative Stuff  Exams Grades   Lecture 0 Lecture 1  CPU Models Addition in different bases Definitions Modular Arithmetic Integer format with word size restriction  Unsigned binary numbers:  Binary Addition Algorithm (BAA)   Negative numbers  Signed Magnitude Representation 1&amp;rsquo;s Complement Problems with Signed Magnitude and 1&amp;rsquo;s Complement 2&amp;rsquo;s complement Intuition behind 2&amp;rsquo;s complement        Administrative Stuff Exams  Midterm: On March 8th, 6-9 pm (tentative)  Check for conflicts   End-of-term exam: Either April 27, evening (6-9 pm) or May 5 in the evening Fill in exam conflicts (by 1/24)  Acceptable excuses: conflicting classes and religious conflicts   Fill in P-credit office hours (By 1/21)  Go to web form The top row indicates the start time of the office hours (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum I</title>
      <link>https://mushetty.me/notes/quantumi/quantumi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 22:19:25 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mushetty.me/notes/quantumi/quantumi/</guid>
      <description>Compilation of notes for Quantum I class for Spring 2023.
 Administrative Stuff Lecture 1  Administrative Stuff  10-minute quizzes (5 questions, multiple choice) 10%:  around February 8 around Around March 1 around April 26   Midterm 25%  around March 22   Final 45% HW 20%  Lecture 1  First HW due 6 pm Jan 25th The Wavefunction  Written in 1 spatial dimension as $\Psi (x,t)$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Notes</title>
      <link>https://mushetty.me/notes/machinelearning/machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 22:19:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mushetty.me/notes/machinelearning/machine/</guid>
      <description>Compilation of notes for Machine Learning class for Spring 2023.
 Administrative Stuff Topic 1  Workflow of Classification Problems (Supervised Learning) Statistical Approach  Classifier     Topic 2 Topic 3 Topic 4 Topic 5 Topic 6 Topic 7 Topic 8 Topic 9  Administrative Stuff  All homework is submitted via Gradescope.  Written parts must be PDFs and be typeset.  Plots and data analysis from programming part must be included in written part   Programming parts are mostly turned in as a separate assignment on Gradescope   40 % HW, 30% Midterm, 30% Final  Topic 1  Inputs encoded as vectors ($x \in X$):  $\vec{x} = &amp;lt;x_{1},x_{2},&amp;hellip;x_{n}&amp;gt;$ Can think of each component as a measurement that you make   Output is another vector ($y \in Y$):  $\vec{y} = &amp;lt;y_{1},y_{2},&amp;hellip;y_{m}&amp;gt;$   Goal is to figure out the function that maps x to y  You only have a limited number of samples from X  You need to make predictions from this limited sample size      Workflow of Classification Problems (Supervised Learning)  $(\vec{x_{1}},y_{1}),(\vec{x_{2}},y_{2})&amp;hellip; \in X \times Y$  Example: $X = \mathbb{R^{d}}$ and $Y = {0,1}$ for a binary classification from a image with d pixels Assumption: there exists a &amp;ldquo;relatively simple&amp;rdquo; function $f^{*}: X \rightarrow Y$ such that $f^{*}(\vec{x_{i}}) = y_{i}$ for most i  $*$ in ML implies some optimum value (in this case, an optimal function) Most includes that possibility that there is some fundamental noise in your data Say someone wrote a number that kind of looks like 7 and kinda looks like 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geophysical Fluid Dynamics</title>
      <link>https://mushetty.me/notes/geophysics/geophysics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 22:19:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mushetty.me/notes/geophysics/geophysics/</guid>
      <description>Compilation of notes for Geophysical Fluid Dynamics class for Spring 2023.
 Administrative Stuff  Administrative Stuff </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Particle Astrophysics &amp; Cosmology</title>
      <link>https://mushetty.me/notes/astroandcosmo/astrocosmo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 22:16:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mushetty.me/notes/astroandcosmo/astrocosmo/</guid>
      <description>Compilation of notes for Astrophysics and Cosmology class for Spring 2023.
 Administrative Stuff Special Relativity  Spacetime Diagrams  Worldline Inertial Frames Postulates of SR Deriving Time Dilation from diagrams Deriving Doppler Shift from Diagram   Metrics  Metric tensor (SR) Covariant versus contravariant vectors Metric in Spherical Coordinates     Non-Euclidean Geometry Classical Cosmology Particle Physics Theory Dark Matter Early Universe Physics Classical and Quantum Theory of the Scalar Field Inflationary cosmology revisited, and structure formation The Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) Primordial Black Holes and Hawking Radiation  Administrative Stuff  Homework assignment assigned as a group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ML Refresher Notes</title>
      <link>https://mushetty.me/notes/mlnotes/ml_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 17:29:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mushetty.me/notes/mlnotes/ml_notes/</guid>
      <description>Here is a compendium of my notes that I took to review for Machine Learning. This was meant to be a quick refresher on concepts and to put everything in one place. For a less cursory version, see the background section under Resources at the course website.
 Probability and Statistics  Basic Concepts  Axioms of Probability Definitions Baye&amp;rsquo;s Rule Expectation   Common Probability Distributions  Bernoulli Distribution Binomial Distribution Poisson Distribution Categorical Distribution Multinomial Distribution Guassian(Normal) Distribution Multivariate Gaussian Distribution Laplace distribution Dirac Delta Distribution Mixtures of Distributions   Common Functions  Logistic sigmoid $\sigma(x)$ Softplus Function $\Zeta(x)$   Information Theory  Self-Information Shannon Entropy Kullback-Leibler (KL) divergence Cross-entropy Exponential Distribution   Chi-squared Distribution  Basics Goodness of Fit (GOF) Independence   T-test  One Sample Two Sample  Paired Unpaired       Linear Algebra  Types of Objects in Linear Algebra Matrix Operations Central Problem of Linear Algebra  Gaussian Elimination Reduced Row Echelon Form (RREF)  Reading of Solutions of Ax=b from RREF     LU Decomposition  LDU Decomposition   Identity and Inverses Vector Spaces  Subspaces  Orthogonal Complements     Linear Transformations  Diagonalization  Change of Basis     Linear Dependence and Span Basis and Dimension Norms Orthogonal Bases Gram-Schmidt and Orthogonal Complements Eigendecomposition Singular Value Decomposition (SVD) Moore-Penrose Pseudoinverse QR Decomposition  Gram-Schmidt   Trace Determinant Kernel, Range, Nullity,Rank  Mapping definitions Kernel Rank and Nullity   Least Squares   Calculus  Probability and Statistics Basic Concepts Axioms of Probability  Probability Measure $P: \mathbb{F} \rightarrow \mathbb{{R}}$ such that  $P(A) \geq 0$ for all $A \in \mathbb{F}$ $P(\Omega) = 1$ If $A_{1},A_{2}&amp;hellip;$ are disjoint events, then  $P(\cup A_{i}) = \Sigma_{i} P(A_{i})$      Definitions  Sample space $\Omega$: The set of all possible outcomes Event space $\mathbb{F}:A$ is a subset of $\Omega$ a random variable quantity that has an uncertain value.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
